all right so how do of people have an
effective conversation because we've all
been involved in meetings and we don't
like them we don't the more people you
add to a group and the more voices you
have to listen to it becomes
exponentially harder because everyone
has to listen to you when you speak and
everyone has to have a turn to speak and
so every person you add exponentially
adds time to the meeting however with
the use of technology and real world
applications that other people use the
word the world cafe has given us a
format that works in the real world to
have a conversation with hundreds of
people you get together in a real space
around cafe like tables in groups of 4
to 5 for a set period of time they give
20 minutes you have a conversation or in
a meaningful question and then everybody
disperses into the room and you have
that same conversation or an added on
conversation with a new question with a
with a new group of people and so with
that in that way the larger group is
also able to have a conversation we with
the technology cooperative are going to
create the platform to facilitate that
online so instead of needing to be in a
physical space at the same place at the
same time you the individual gets to say
when you're available in a 24 hour
period will be 48 time slots of a half
an hour each you get to participate be
given people to talk to in tables of
three to four and you can participate in
none or up to 48 if you wanted to you
can't be in two places at once and we
suggest not staying awake for 24 hours
to continually have a conversation but
you could there's gonna be people who
have conversations in multiple languages
and that's how the greater world has a
conversation all around the globe every
day every 24-hour period will have a
question
and we get to submit and vote on what
those questions are as the users grow as
we have thousands and tens of thousands
of people we can branch off into areas
of expertise if we want to we can talk
about you could have a question every
day about plastic in the ocean and how
we actually solve it and that group of
people getting together having those
conversations will be able to more
effectively create a solution then how
we're all scattered in different
directions and not able to have a
conversation currently when we start
we're gonna be having conversations
about the technological cooperative and
greater issues on the planet to see the
power of a conversation and work out the
kinks of having a conversation with a
thousand people on existing platforms
will have our platform that is the
platform to organize and tell people
where they need to get to but it'll be
hosted on existing infrastructure on
zoom' on a pier in on skype on something
that already is there so we're not
spending millions of dollars recreating
video conferencing but there's gonna be
a time when of course we have to spend
that money and create that ourselves
because we don't want them to be able to
take it away or they change a policy and
it will affect us but we can start with
an app that costs under a hundred
thousand for sure and helps people sign
up say when they're available the topics
they want to talk about and together we
can have a meaningful conversation
because we're gonna give you people to
talk to and as issues arrive when
there's let's say conflict we can look
at why that conflict happened we can
look at how we grow and learn through
conflict as well as how do we keep
people safe from conflict who don't want
to be in conflict we are going to figure
out how to have a conversation with
thousands of people by having
conversations with it'll start with
smaller group people I mean I want like
five people to work with but then we
need to all be available in the same
time at the same place and even that is
hard too hard to figure out I constantly
want to start book clubs and things when
I read a book and I'm like wait not
everyone's reading the book at the same
time then we have to figure out who
wants to have a conversation around this
book at the right time just having that
platform just having that to
it helps you create a group around your
time in your place and a schedule will
already have a positive positive impact
it'll be like say Peron I'll be like
Meetup but online and if we're creating
it with the idea that that same tool can
be used for different things even if in
the beginning it's only used for our
conversation we can easily create it for
every other purpose and have people sign
on and say I don't I don't care about so
I can want to technological cooperative
but what would bring meaning to my life
is I was able to talk about poverty or
trains or planes or penguins I don't
care what the topic is when people able
to meaningfully come together and have a
conversation with other people it's a
lot harder to divide us it's a lot
harder to convince people that people
don't care and that people are evil and
bad when you can see people and see that
there is humanity in all of us there is
intelligence in all of us and all we
have to do is bring as an individual is
bring yourself to the table exactly as
you are and we will figure out together
how to make that work using existing
technology and creating our own please
like and subscribe
can I'll see you tomorrow